Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise number.
In this exercise, we are asked to find the time complexity of this algorithm, so find the time complexity
of this for loop starting from I equal to one I less than or equal math, the power to of and and and
I plus plus and system the doubt that print this message.
Both the video and think about this exercise, and I hope you write your answer in the comments below
to see how the activity and how their their participation in this course will affect your progress.
Now.
Solving this exercises are very important to understand all the concerns.
So please write them down and try to solve them and write these these exercises in your copy book in
order to review them later when you have an exam or an interview.
As every loop, we have to start with the conditions, with that initial condition, with the stop condition
and the increment then crunch this Lou is equal to one.
So we will start with one here.
We will stop at I less than or equal math, the power of two and and this library math, we used the
power method from it.
And we have best do and power and this will result into power.
And so if we enter any number and here or we pass any number and to this law, it will go through from
one till two to power.
And if we pass like four, if an equal to four.
There is also a condition here.
I told you I increment is A-plus plus, so all the elements from one to tell to power and are going
to be passed through this loop.
OK, we have here all of one.
So we have it is very simple.
So this is a constant oh of what?
And as as I told you, this loop will go through from one til two to power and and acting and moving
from one to two and an all through all these elements.
OK.
Let's take an example.
An equal and equal to four.
OK, so what are the elements if an equal to four at it is, these are from one.
Due to the power for which is due to power for two to.
Three, four, five, six seven.
Eight.
Two times to four times to eight times to 16.
So two to power four is 16.
OK, so nine.
Then.
11, 12, 13, 14, 15 and 16.
So.
This loop will go through all of these elements 16.
Times 16 iteration and printing this system print as 16 times.
If we go and took and an equal to five, this will execute this statement as to two power five OK.
It is 16 times.
Two is equal to 32 times.
OK, if we took an equal to six, it will give us two to power.
Six.
So it would result in 64 times.
Therefore, that time complexity of this exercise is, oh of two, an OK.
It's due to power eight, for example, it will execute at two hundred fifty six times.
OK, so therefore all equal to two and power and OK, this is the time complexity.
It is the power.